All right. Well, thank you all for withstanding the rain and for being here with us.
I'm Congresswoman Ilhan Omar. I represent Minnesota's 5th Congressional District.
I'm filled with sadness.
Sad for the Palestinian and Jewish people who have been rallying across this country, begging.
Begging for their leaders to stand up for humanity.
Not being able to be given the space to grieve the loss that they have experienced.
And not being allowed to be represented by people who can see their love, their compassion,
their interest in saving lives.
I'm also saddened by the fact that 535 members of Congress could come together in one breath,
fully condemn the horrors of what Israelis experienced.
Only, maybe a few handful of them who could get to the point of saying,
we condemn the slaughter of Palestinian children, of mothers, of fathers, of grandmothers, of grandfathers.
Where is your humanity?
An atrocity.
Bodies pie leveled.
Then we dropped in a whole year in our people.
Thousands of Americans is stuck in Gaza.
Big in Gaza?
Less important than the one living in Israel?
Citizens of Gaza.
But you can't tell Netanyahu not to bomb the South because there are Americans there.
Condemning that Israel has bombed.
Humanitarian aid is supposed to get through, through Egypt,
where we are asking our citizens, lip service, and hope for a negotiated humanitarian access.
It's scary.
It's responsible for this.
And not a single condemnation comes from our caucus leadership or any member of Congress.
There are members who condemn us for asking for peace, for a ceasefire.
The most simplest thing.
So many people across the world are calling for a ceasefire.
So many leaders are calling for a ceasefire.
Over 65% of our own population here in the United States is calling for a ceasefire in the latest polling.
What are we doing?
We survived war when I was 8 years old.
Picture this because it gets lost in all of the conversations.
Even when they interview people who are living under bombardment in Gaza,
they do not ask questions that address their humanity.
They do not ask questions that address what's happening to their psyche as they are living through this bombardment.
So I want to give you an image of what it feels like.
Imagine sitting in your house, hearing, hearing the noise that announces that you might vanish at any given moment.
On to yourself, this wall, as you can, because all you are hoping for is if that bomb drops in your house,
that you can at least night, every week, every month.
Immediately, a rocket fell on the house I lived in.
41 years old.
It's right next to the wall.
That trauma has not left me.
I need you all to understand this.
It's not just now.
Hashtag for ceasefire for Gaza many, many times.
People cleansed.
Be patient.
Multiple wars.
Millions of their people displaced, unable to visit their ancestral lands.
Continuous harassment, jailing, killing, with impunity, empathy, of lawmakers in this country who are responsible.
Who are responsible in not creating the condition for the Palestinians to realize their own self-determination.
To live as free people, to have their humanity intact, for them to decide where they will have.
Family members that live in other villages from one another.
Sanity.
And we can no longer stand for this insanity.
And we would like for people to stop harassing us, for caring about the humanity of people.
To stop harassing us, for asking for war to end.
Because those of us who lived in war don't want to see war continue.
You might be fine with that.
Your stock prices might go up with war.
I am not fine with weapons being sent to kill children.
Like the ones I played with.
I am not fine with that.
So yes, you can threaten me.
You can harass me.
You can follow me around.
But I am never going to stop saying Palestinians deserve freedom.
That we need to free Palestine.
And I am never going to stop saying that there is no way that we should allow incending more bombardments to kill Palestinians.
Thank you.